MADELEINE KEMENY: Experienced Design Professional: Print, Exhibit, & Web mostly web examples • mostly print & exhibit examples • contact me

SUMMARY

Madeleine is an experienced graphic designer and project manager with a strong background in branded marketing communications. She has engaged in both corporate and nonprofit sector projects at all levels, from strategy development to end-user deliverable.

During a sabbatical from design, Madeleine rose to the level of Pastry Chef through working in beloved local restaurants and Michelin Star awarded kitchens. She managed staff, schedules, ordering, and event menus; developed and tested recipes; and produced daily menus of seasonal desserts to please up to 800 patrons a night. But, she's ready to return to design, so bring on the logos, web sites, spaces, and apps!

Specialties: Branding. Environmental design. Print collateral. Marketing communications. Team management. UX/UI development. Seeing the larger picture and getting it done!

EXPERIENCE

Self-employed Design Consultant: 7/1996 – Present. More than 100 clients in the United States

Projects have included branding, logos, annual reports, marketing communications, board trainings, strategic planning, tradeshow displays, magazines, educational publishing, website consulting, signage, environments, videography, invitations, development and capital campaigns, illustrated infographics, art direction, social media, and script writing.

Clients have included restaurants, youth and family services agencies, actors, universities, tech startups, industrial consulting firms, property holding corporations, art galleries, fitness studios, houses of worship, law firms, hospitals, health foundations, natural area preservation organizations, medical practices, social enterprises, museums, professional associations, libraries, design and architecture firms, primary schools, sports teams, and political campaigns.

Pastry Cook to Pastry Chef: 11/2013 - Present. Various Restaurants, Greater Chicago Area, Illinois

Responsibilities have included typical executive-level restaurant management tasks, PR photography art direction, writing business plans and operating agreements, brand management, special events, and systems development; daily production of menu items.

Demo Specialist: 11/2013 – 7/2014. Whole Foods Market, Evanston, Illinois

Developed recipes and live demos of cooking techniques and serving suggestions; provided customer service for menu ideas, purchases, store policies, and general information; conducted classroom format cooking lessons for private groups.

Designer to Director of Design: 9/1994 – 7/2013. Various Design Consultancies, Chicago, Illinois

Developed branding and design for annual reports, educational materials, and other print communications for nonprofit and private sector organizations, including professional associations, youth and family services agencies, think-tanks, medical associations, trade periodicals, talent and entertainment management firms, cultural institutions, philanthropic organizations, universities. unions, daycare centers, libraries, and industrial manufacturers.

EDUCATION

Rhode Island School of Design: 1994, Bachelor of Fine Arts.

Northwestern University: 2019, Certificate, Full-stack Web Development.